（フリーセル）ママ…。
回想
Mama...
（ピノクル）
あいつが　フリーセルを悲しませた…。
He made Freecell sad...
あいつが　フリーセルを壊した…。
He broke Freecell...
（ヘルベルト）大門カイトとゲームをしたい？
You want to play a game with Daimon Kaito?
ほう　それは　それは…。
Well, what's this I hear?
君のような　やる気のある部下を
持ち　私も上官として　鼻が高いよ。
As your superior, I'm proud to have such an enthusiastic subordinate.
だが…　覚えておきたまえ。
But!
Remember this well.
君ごときが　私に意見を言うなど
１，０００年　早いのだよ。
Your lowly kind are a thousand years too early to have your opinions heard by me!
（ホイスト）いかがなさいましたか？
ピノクル様。
What might be the trouble, Sir Pinochle?
うふっ…。
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
Pinochle's Resolution
（カイト）その話　本当なんだろうな？
Is that true?
（ピノクル）ああ　お前がゲームに勝てば
全部　教えてあげるよ。
Yes. If you win the game, I'll tell you everything.
お前とフリーセルの間に
何があったのか。
Everything that happened between you and Freecell.
（ダウト）レプリカだと！？
A replica?!
Yes. Eve's ring was definitely a replica.
（ミゼルカ）ええ　イブのリングは
間違いなく　レプリカだった。
バカな。　オルペウス・オーダーに
選ばれし者が　レプリカ・リングなど…。
Impossible!
She was chosen by the Orpheus Order! She must have...
でも　あれは確かに…。
（メランコリィ）もう　お姉様！
Even so, I'm sure...
Sister, don't just leave me out of the fun!
私を仲間外れにして　一体
何をしてるのかしら？
What are you doing?
あぁ…。
お前には関係ないことだ。
It's none of your business.
向こうに行っていろ。
ぷう。　フン！
Get lost.
オルペウス・オーダーには　私たちも知らない
何かが　あるのかもしれない。
We may not know the Orpheus Order as well as we think we do.
だとしても…　それも
クロンダイク様のご意志だ。
Nevertheless, that is Lord Klondike's will.
（フリーセル）うふふっ。
（ホイスト）今しばらくお待ちください。
フリーセル様。
Please be patient a while longer, Sir Freecell.
I know, Whist.
分かってるよ　ホイスト。
カイトとパズルタイムを始められるのは
僕だけだ。
I'm the only one who can have puzzle time with Kaito.
本当の…　パズルタイムをね…。
True puzzle time, that is.
I am relieved to hear that.
それを伺い　安心いたしました。
どうです？
ご一緒に　いかがですか？
Would you mind accompanying me?
面白いものを
ご覧に入れましょう。
We may see something fascinating.
（ピノクル）どうだい？
これが　僕の作ったゲーム。
What do you think?
This is the game I made.
名付けて　インフェルノタワー。
I call it Inferno Tower.
この塔には　１３の段がある。
The tower has thirteen levels.
All thirteen have a color matching puzzle.
そして　全ての段に
色合わせのパズルがある。
このパズルは　ダイヤルが接する部分の
色を　全て合わせると　クリア。
A puzzle is cleared when you match the colors on all the rings.
When we're on the same level, we get the same problem.
同じ段のとき　お前と俺には
同じ問題が出題される。
Of course, the faster one wins.
当然　早く解いた方の勝ち。
負けた方のゴンドラは　１段上がる。
The loser's gondola rises one level.
１段　上がるごとに
問題の難易度も上がっていく。
The higher you are, the more difficult the puzzles get.
最終的に　先に相手を
最上段に上げた方の勝ちってわけ。
Which means, the player who can raise the other to the top first wins.
（フリーセル）
へぇ～！　今度は　ピノクルかい？
Oh, so it's Pinochle this time?
（ホイスト）
はい。　ピノクル様ご自身のご要望で。
クロンダイク様の許可も得ております。
Yes. He wished for it himself. He doesn't have Lord Klondike's consent either.
He wanted to do it himself?
自分から　言い出したのかい？
１人じゃ　何もできないと
思ってたけど。
I thought he could never do anything by himself.
最新のデータで　ピノクル様のリングを→
Using the most recent data,
we have upgraded Sir Pinochle's ring to the Orpheus ring's gamma version.
オルペウス・リング・ガンマに
アップグレードいたしました。
（フリーセル）
ふ～ん。　それで　リングに　完全に
飲み込まれちゃったってわけか…。
Oh, so the ring's finally taken him over?
かわいそうだね　レプリカは。
I feel sorry for the replica users.
（ピノクル）じゃあ　始めようか。
Now, let's begin!
ああ…。
インフェルノタワー　プレー！
Fine.
Inferno Tower, play!
（ギャモン）気をつけろ　カイト！　また
訳の分かんねえこと　ほざいて→
Be careful, Kaito!
He might start blabbering nonsense to make you lose your cool!
てめえの心を　乱す作戦に
出るかもしれねえぜ！
フッ　そんな心配は要らないよ。
You don't have to worry about that.
ウソも　まやかしも言わない。
今日の俺は　本気だからね。
I won't lie or make stuff up.
I'm serious today.
（３人）ああ！
（ノノハ）えっ！？　何よ　あれ？
What's that?!
溶鉱炉！？
（ピノクル）相手を最上段に
上げ　さらに　もう１勝すれば→
A smelter?!
If you raise the other person to the top, then win once more,
負けた方のゴンドラは
あの中に真っ逆さまってね。
the loser's gondola will fall straight down in there!
てめえ…。
ウフフッ　言ったろ？　本気だって…。
You son of a...!
I told you, I'm serious.
本気で　お前を倒し
この世界から消してやるよ。
I'm going to defeat you and erase your existence from the world,
大門カイト！
Daimon Kaito!
Stop! This is too dangerous!
（ノノハ）ダメだよ！
こんな危険なパズル！
そうだよ！
Yeah!
これじゃあ　勝っても
カイトが　あいつの命を！
Even if you win, you'll end up killing him!
もう止められねえ！
You can't stop it now.
What do you want? Why are you doing this?
一体　何が目的？
どうして　こんなことするの！？
大門カイトは　他人の心を傷つけ
踏みにじった。
Daimon Kaito broke someone's heart and stomped on the pieces.
消されて当然のやつなのさ。
あのフリーセルって人のこと！？
He's naturally bound to be eliminated.
Are you talking about Freecell?
大門カイトは　フリーセルとの約束を
破ったんだよ。
Daimon Kaito broke his promise to Freecell.
そして　フリーセルの母親は死んだ。
うっ。
Then Freecell's mother died!
（アナ）カイトの手が止まった。
あのバカ！
Kaito's hand stopped!
That idiot!
フリーセルは　母親のことが好きだった。
Freecell loved his mother.
大好きだったんだ。　なのに！
Really loved her! And yet!
Kaito might've broken his promise.
カイトが約束を破ったのは
本当かもしれない。
彼のお母さんが亡くなったのも。
でも！
Freecell's mother might've died too.
But!
そうだよ！　その２つに　一体
何の関係があるっていうのさ！
Yeah! What do those two things have to do with each other?!
そいつは　大門カイトが勝ったら
教えてあげるよ。
I'll tell you if Daimon Kaito can win.
俺が死ぬ間際にね。
As a present before I die.
真実を知ると同時に
お前は罪を背負うんだ。
The moment you know the truth, you'll shoulder a new sin.
The sin of killing me!
俺を殺したという罪を。
Kaito?!
カイトが！？
ビシッと　しやがれ！　カイト！
Get a fucking hold of yourself, Kaito!
それに　大門カイトは
ウソつきだからね。　うふふっ。
And that's not all... Daimon Kaito is a liar.
えっ！？
ウソつき？
A liar?
Yes! Daimon Kaito is a liar!
そう…　大門カイトは　ウソつきだ。
ウソをついて　フリーセルを傷つけた！
He lied and hurt Freecell!
約束を破った自分を
正当化するために→
To justify that he broke his promise,
フリーセルの悪い噂を
言いふらしたんだ。
he spread evil rumors about Freecell!
噂を信じ込ませるために
周りに取り入った。
He sucked up to everyone to make them believe his story.
ウソをつき
調子のいいことを言ってね。
He's always been a liar and a fraud.
カイトが　そんなこと
するはずがない！
Kaito would never do that!
うん！
あんにゃろう　また　でたらめを！
Yeah!
He's playing dirty again!
違う…。
（３人）えっ！？
No...
ウソだけど　ウソじゃない。
It's a lie, but it's not.
ウソだけど　本当のこと。
It's a lie, but it's true.
ウソだけど　本当？
It's a lie, but it's true?
（ピノクル）お前は　そういうやつなのさ
大門カイト。
You're that kind of a guy, Daimon Kaito.
約束を破り　ウソをつき　裏切り
大勢の人間を傷つけた。
You lie, betray, and hurt many people.
その罪を　今　ここで償え！
Atone for those sins now!
Kaito!
カイト！
消えろ！　消えてしまえ！
Die! Die and vanish, Daimon Kaito.
大門カイト～！
そうかもしれねえな。
かっ！？
That may be true.
クロスフィールド学院にいた頃の俺は→
Back at Crossfield Academy, I might've been a nasty guy.
確かに
嫌なやつだったかもしれねえ。
誰にも　心を開かねえで…。
でも　それは…。
I wouldn't open up to anyone.
But that was...
どんな事情があったって
悪いもんは悪い。
The circumstances don't matter. What's bad is bad.
俺が覚えてるかどうかなんて
関係ねえ。
It doesn't matter if I remember it or not.
多分　お前らを傷つけちまった事に
変わりはねえのさ。
I probably really did hurt you guys.
でも…　だからこそ　知りてえんだ。
俺が　何をしちまったのか…。
But that's all the more reason I want to know.
I want to know what I did,
お前らに　ちゃんと謝るためにも。
あっ　謝る…　だと？
so I can apologize to you!
You want to apologize?
ふ　ふざけるな！
Don't give me the bullshit!
この世界から消える以外に
お前にできる償いはない！
The only way you can atone for this is death!
だから　俺は負けねえ。　本当の事を
知るためにも　絶対に勝つ！
I won't lose!
I must win to learn the truth!
本当に　カイトが
彼らを傷つけたって言うの？
Did Kaito really hurt them?
アナが思うに
真実は１つじゃない。
I think... there's more than one truth.
どんなものにも　裏と表がある。
Every coin has two sides.
見えているものだけが
真実じゃない…。
What you see isn't all of the truth.
よし！　追いついた！
Okay, he caught up!
I won't lose!
負けない…　俺は負けない！
オルペウス・リングが！？
暴走してんのか！？
The Orpheus ring!
Is it overloading?
許さない…　フリーセルを
フリーセルを傷つけた大門カイトを→
You must pay...
You hurt... You hurt Freecell...
You must pay for this, Daimon Kaito!
絶対に…　絶対に許さない！
本当に　お友達のため？
Is this really for your friend?
本当に　あの子は
君のお友達なの？
Is he really your friend?
本当は…。
Really...?
（ピノクル）
うるさい…　うるさい　うるさい！
Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
ぐわっ　ああ。
フリーセルは　俺のたった１人の…
友達なんだ～！
Freecell is my one and only friend!
あと１問で　カイトの勝ちだ。
One more and Kaito wins.
でも　カイトが勝ったら　あいつは…。
But if Kaito wins, Pinochle will...
どうした？　問題を解きなよ。
What's wrong?
Solve the puzzle!
いえっ。　解け～！
Solve it!
もう　やめようぜ！
えへぇ！？
Stop it!
勝負はついた。　俺の勝ちだ。
The game is over.
I won. There's no point in continuing!
これ以上　続ける意味はねえ。
ふざけるな～！
Don't screw with me!
Kaito!
カイト！
何が　勝負はついただ！
まだ　これからだ！
The game's over my ass! It's just getting started!
（ゴンドラの上がる音）
いいさ！　お前が　その気なら！
Fine! If you're gonna do that...
俺が～！
I will...
はぁ　はぁ…　なぜだ！？
どうして解かない？
Why?!
Why won't you fight?
お前　フリーセルのためだって
言ったよな。
You said this is for Freecell.
たった１人の友達だって。
はぁ！
That he's your one and only friend.
そ…　それが　どうした…。
S-So what?
もし俺だったら　友達が俺のために
誰かを傷つけるのも→
You know, if it were me,
I'd hate to see my friends hurt someone
誰かに傷つけられるのも
ごめんだな。
or be hurt for my sake.
（ホイスト）
どうやら　ここまでのようですね。
It would seem the game is over.
Parting is such sweet sorrow.
お別れは　つらいものです。
うわぁ～～！
Kaito moved the gondola so that it'd get caught by the beam!
カイトが　ゴンドラを動かして
支柱に引っかけやがった。
ヨシオ君　発進だ！
Yoshio, go!
ほらよ。
あぁ…　お前　どうして…。
Grab on!
Why would you...?
お前　本当は　フリーセルと
友達になりたいんだろう。
You just want to be friends with Freecell, right?
うははっ…。
あいつと　パズルをしたいんだろう？
You just want to puzzle with him, right?
だったら　してみろよ。
まずは　そこから…　ってな。
Then try. That's the first step.
助かっちゃったね…　ピノクル。
He was saved.
リングは処分できました。
問題はありません。
The ring was destroyed, and that's what matters.
ヘルベルト様には　ピノクル様は
お亡くなりになったと→
Let's report to Sir Herbert that Sir Pinochle passed away.
報告しておきましょう。
（ヘルベルト）何だと！
（カップの割れる音）
What?!
（ミゼルカ）ピノクルが　死んだ！？
はい…　事故で…。
Pinochle... died?!
Yes, in an accident.
（ダウト）ふ～ん。
ハッ！　使い物にならんと
思っていたが→
I didn't think he had any skill,
何の役にも立たんうちに
くたばるとは→
but to think he went and died before I could use him somehow!
虫けらにも劣るやつだ…　ぐはっ。
A pile of shit could outperform him.
な　何をする！？
W-What are you doing?!
オルペウス・オーダーは　クロンダイク様に
選ばれし栄光ある騎士。
The Orpheus Order is a group of glorious knights chosen by Lord Klondike.
お前も　騎士の端くれなら
死者に対する礼節を知れ！
If you have even an ounce of knightliness in you, show some respect to the dead!
（フリーセル）バカだよね　ピノクル…。
You are a fool, Pinochle.
本当は　僕…　ママなんか
大っ嫌いなのに…。
The truth is...
I hate my mother.
うふふっ。
（ピノクル）ごめんなさい…
全部　僕のせいなんだ。
I'm sorry. It was all my fault.
お前のせい？
あの時　カイトが約束を破ったあと→
Your fault?
Back then, after you broke your promise,
フリーセルは　「もう一度
カイトに会いたい」って言ったんだ。
Freecell said he wanted to meet you again.
Huh?
えっ！？
そうなの？
Really?
いや　あれ以来　俺は
あいつに会ってねえ。
No, I haven't seen him since then.
フリーセルの話を聞いて　僕が
カイトに伝えておくって言ったんだ。
When Freecell told me that, I said I'd tell you.
だけど…。
伝えなかったってか！？
But...
You never did?!
なんで！？
Why?
怖かったんだ…
２人が仲よくなって→
I was scared...
I thought if you two got along, I'd be left alone!
自分が　独りぼっちになってしまう
ような気がして…。
それが　バレるのが嫌で
フリーセルにウソをついた。
I was afraid he'd find out, so I lied to him.
カイトが　フリーセルの悪口を言ったって。
I told him you were badmouthing him.
信じてもらえるように
カイトの悪口を言いふらした。
I spread bad rumors about you so that they'd believe me.
I got more friends with my made-up stories.
調子のいいことを言って
友達も増やした。
カイトの悪い噂を広めるためにね。
Just to spread evil rumors about Kaito...
それって！？
That's...
That's what you said during the puzzle!
パズルの最中に　カイトの仕業だって
言ってたことじゃない？
自分のことだったのかよ！
つ～か　やっぱウソ言ってたのか！
You were talking about yourself?!
You really were lying then!
違う！　ご　ごめん…。
No!
I'm sorry...
でも　あの時は　本当に
カイトがやったと　思い込んでたんだ。
But I really believed it was Kaito who did it.
どうしてだか
自分でも分からないけど…。
I don't really know why.
あっ！？　ウソだけど…　本当…。
It's a lie, but it's true...
うん。
ああ？　どういうこった？
What does that mean?
彼は　ウソがバレるのを
恐れていた。
He was afraid of his lie being uncovered.
おそらく　その思いが　リングのせいで
ゆがめられてしまったんだろうね。
The ring must've twisted that fear.
記憶の書き換えといった
ところかな？
It may have even overwritten his memories.
えっ！？　記憶の書き換え？
Overwriting his memories?!
（キュービック）
罪の意識と　ウソがバレてしまう
恐怖から逃れるために→
To escape the fear of being found out and the guilt of lying,
記憶を書き換えたんだ。　自分の
したことを　カイトのしたことにね。
his memories were changed.
He remembered what he did as if Kaito had done it.
そのうえで　カイトが居なくなれば
ウソは永遠にバレず　真実となる。
And if Kaito died, the lie would never be found out,
and it would become the truth.
もう一つだけ　教えてくれ。
えっ！？
Tell me just one more thing.
俺が　フリーセルの母親を　悲しみの中で
死なせた…　あれは本当なのか？
You said I made Freecell's mother die in sadness.
Is that true?
分からない。
分からないって？
I don't know...
How can you not know?
カイトが約束を破ったのも　フリーセルの
お母さんが死んだのも　事実さ。
It's true that you broke your promise and that Freecell's mother died.
だけど　その２つの間に
どんな関係があるのか→
But I don't know how those two are connected either.
僕にも分からないんだ。
でも　あの子は
それを信じてるんだね。
But he believes it, right?
あの子にとっては　それが真実。
To him, that's the truth.
本当に　ごめん！
僕のせいで　カイトもフリーセルも…。
I'm really sorry!
It's my fault that you and Freecell...
初めに約束を破ったのは　俺だ。
そのことに　変わりはねえさ。
I broke my promise first.
There's no changing that.
You should rest for now.
今は　体を休めて。
そうそう。
Yeah!
つらいのに　全部
話してくれて　ありがとう。
It must've been tough to tell us all that.
ピノクル君も　もう
私たちの仲間だよ。
You're our friend now too, Pinochle!
へっ！　それは　どうかな？
まだ　分かんねえぜ。
I wonder about that!
We can't be sure!
ギャモン君！
ああ　ギャモンの言うとおりだ。
Gammon!
Yup, it's just as Gammon says!
カイトまで！
まだ　本当のお前とは
パズルしてねえからな。
You too, Kaito?!
I haven't puzzled with the real you yet.
元気になったら
一緒にパズルしようぜ！
Let's puzzle after you get well!
まずは　そこから…　ってな！
That's the first step!
あぁ…。　あ～…　ありがとう。
（泣き声）
Thank you!
うふっ。
へっ。
ふ～ん。
いやっ　フン！
フリーセルを　フリーセルも救ってほしい…。
Freecell...
Please save Freecell...
オルペウス・オーダーから…
クロンダイクから…。
From the Orpheus Order... From Klondike...
あぁ…　クロンダイク？
Huh? Klondike?
（カップの割れる音）
（ヘルベルト）くそっ！　くそ～っ！
何が礼節だ！　あいつの方こそ
礼儀知らずではないか！
Respect?! He's the one who should learn some respect!
ガキの分際で　この私に
汚い手で触れるとは！
How dare that mere filthy boy touch me?!
（ホイスト）
度重なる失敗に　ピノクル様の死。
Your repeated failures and now Sir Pinochle's death...
クロンダイク様は　ヘルベルト様の指揮能力に
疑問も抱かれております。
Lord Klondike has started having doubts about your leadership abilities.
愚か者が　勝手に死んだだけだ！
That fool died on his own!
そんなことまで
私の知ったことではない！
What does that have to do with me?!
おっしゃるとおりです。　ですが
クロンダイク様は　大変お怒りのご様子。
It's just as you say.
However, Lord Klondike seems to be furious.
はぁ～！　部下に恵まれず
上司には誤解を受け→
I have incompetent underlings and my superiors don't understand anything...
私は　なんと不幸な星の下に
生まれたのだ。
What an unlucky star I must have been born under!
I know of a good way to calm Lord Klondike's rage.
１つだけ　クロンダイク様のお怒りを
静める　いい方法がございます。
何だ？　言ってみろ！
What?! Tell me!
それは…。
Well...
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt